Call the word of the mind respect of my seat of Council for the day of the 16th.
Item 2, Proclamation of the Crayon August 17th through the 24th of 2016, for an all-in-reak.
Read the Proclamation.
That course in the week of August 15th through the 21st of 2016 is for an all-in-reak,
in the city of Miami, Albert County, Oklahoma.
Whereas the impact of international heroic work of Bluejack in Miami,
the state of Fort Hollings should be commemorated to her hometown in her hometown to meet again,
where she is designed to appreciate for groundbreaking work,
pursuing libertarian and recognition for all men and women,
and where is the efforts to instill liberation from oppression and violence
or reflecting the workings of the community crisis center,
incorporated in the advocacy and philosophy,
and where is the attention to focus as the education and awareness of front-homes work,
or what she stood for, and what it is important to all people,
including but not limited to the citizens of Miami, Oklahoma.
Thank you.
You need that, Alicia.
Isn't about here to take it?
No.
All right.
Yeah.
If we could.
Before we leave this slide, we'd like to talk about the street idea that we...
Okay.
Today was the firm Holland luncheon, which I attended,
and there was some discussion about the possibility of placing a secondary name
on a street south.
It would be east.
Yes.
In the honor of Furnhaul and where the crisis center has their Furnhaul and facility.
And so I'd discuss that with Mr. Croutoff and thought that that might be a good time
to bring that up for just general discussion at this point.
I don't think that's ever been done here in Miami,
but you'll see this in many other cities, large and small,
which you actually do not change the address.
So if it was still be a street nobody would have to change their postal address or anything like that.
But usually on the street side there would be a secondary sign,
which is basically an honorary name in honor of somebody like Furnhaul.
And along the slide, especially with one of the remaining thoroughfares,
it's problematic to rename it officially,
but it would be something very nice to be able to do it in Furnhaul and Furnhaul
in front of a facility that's named after her.
David, I've been the past council addresses at one time.
I thought it was, but I'm hearing me maybe.
Neil, I recall the council.
passing some sort of proclamation with a lot of the firm,
but I don't recall the details.
Yeah, we passed a proclamation last year too, right?
But I thought the street discussion also came up.
About a year or so ago, they talked to me about that.
And I invited them to follow up with me.
And I think when Ben mentioned that to me, he said,
well, I think that's the follow up.
And they mentioned it to him today.
OK.
I'm thrilled to begin putting on the skills of personal parents
in about a wish to address the council on the agenda items.
Ben and Anne.
I don't know if all consent to join them.
The staff is recommending five through 11 to keep
close to them considering the agenda and the directions
not most of the approving around you, haven't you?
Yeah.
You know, further discussion, I make most of the approving.
All second.
Western?
Aye.
Johnson?
Lewis?
Aye.
Forced.
I'm 12.
The final two four insumations are the cure for the very
chicken.
Fick.
Jessica here 15 16 outside of organizational contracts.
Jill.
This is a housekeeping item.
The contracts we're talking about are last year, fiscal year
15 16.
There were two of our outside orgs that some of the requirements
were reporting requirements.
And they had a specific date that they had to turn the reports in.
There were some reports that were late.
So just to move forward and make sure we're all on the same page
for the 16 17 contracts, which I'll bring to you next meeting,
I'll bring the applications and the contracts.
We'd kind of like to just close this one out and make sure it's all,
it's just like I said, it's housekeeping.
We've changed our tracking methods a little bit,
because I'm going to take partial blame for the tracking.
The contract did say that they were supposed to turn the reports
into the city clerk.
Sometimes they did, sometimes they came other places.
So there was just a little bit of confusion even internally.
So we fixed that internally.
We are now going to make sure that before anything goes on a claim,
or before utility credit gets credited,
we will make sure that they have met all the requirements
of their contracts to that point.
That's moving forward from 16 17.
But I'm just asking that you accept this as their cure
for the breach for 15.
It sounds worse than it is, but they did submit the reports.
So they have to respond to the report every quarter.
Yes, by the first of the next month,
but we've actually changed that day to the 15th of that month.
OK.
I think it's very important to reiterate what Jill said.
The next contracts will have provisions in it
that if those do not come in on time, the next reimbursement will not
happen until there's a cure.
It's going to be until it's corrected.
Because that's one of the problems as we have these agreements.
But yet.
We didn't have that connect with the reimbursement.
Now we've made that connection, okay?
Yes.
So everybody's well aware of it.
And again, these are reporting requirements and things
such as that.
And then I know I've talked with Grand Gateway today.
I've talked to the others.
And they understood completely and they're working with us.
Okay.
There's no question I'm like a motion to approve.
You'll be recommendation.
On second.
Johnson.
All right.
Lewis?
Western?
Aye.
Forster?
I'm 13 a lot of my my horseman's association,
the period of two weeks to cure its breach of the market rate.
Team.
But a market team, two thousand, 14,
lease agreement with the city of Miami.
Jamie?
Yep.
We're here today to share the contract with the horseman's association.
They are back to some of the rent.
And then also in the contract is states that they have to maintain the property
and we need it.
We actually went down there this past week for the fair to mow it and maintain it.
The cost on that would be actually 59.58.
That is the cost for my three employees to mow it.
So we asked to cure that also cost into the rent that they're passed to and we'll have
them two weeks to pay that.
Jamie, can you tell on how much rent is passed to you?
Four months passed to.
Be $600.
So they're total of extra be $600.
59.
One thing I would like to point out.
And the reason we have this item on each end as a cure item as well.
Logologist indicated about some housekeeping and some procedures.
This was an agreement that went into effect in 2014.
And even the first year there was never an action to take it to you to renew it.
It just basically went through.
We need to track this a little bit better than we had better.
In fact, that's the contract management process that Christa and Jill Lumin in putting
in place.
So to a great degree, while we do need to have payments made, we do need to have them to
live up to the aspects of the contract in regard to mowing and maintaining the property.
It's great too.
We probably if we had caught this earlier, we probably could have worked with them a lot quicker
or brought something to you, or basically say that there's really technically not a contract.
And I'm not going to try to, we've got two attorneys in the room and we're not going
to try to do their job.
Well, we thought the best thing to do is just to say that we're going to be following
this much more closely, but instead of just declaring it no-envoyed or something like that,
to have a cure opportunity so we can continue on with what the original entity agreement
will be back in November of 2014 or March of 2014, excuse me.
And you have been in contact with them and they're working towards, yes, working towards
your divorce.
That'd be it.
I'd like to make a motion to approve Jamie's Reckon Dachman.
Second.
Thompson?
Aye.
Forster?
Lewis?
Aye.
Western?
I'm 14.
There's Lish Perl and Community Finance of Fort Feeweb and Trans-Priny Property Ownership of 11.
Lots of clinical housing partners for the construction of 18.
Single family dwellings located on infield lots on 24 units located in the Harvest Church of Historic Building.
Well, I will thank Christy McLean for putting together the BA on this.
And she's been working with Tammy Creason, who is here.
And you may have some questions of Tammy to bring you up to speed.
But you might remember that earlier we approved or we got the approval of the Route 66 landing.
And that is the modification and work on the Farmers Exchange Building, which,
I call the Robinson Building, which would be the harvest time church, but it's immediately
catacorned to the Coleman Theatre.
And in working with, we've discussed a number of things that we are doing and looking at this as a,
basically an economic development project.
So to be able to help with this, we have an item here, which is an action request for you to approve,
which is transferring 11 info lots.
We're talking about a fee waiver of impact fees, building permits and inspections.
Now they will still need to get all their inspections and all their permits, but we're just basically waiting the fees.
In the parking lot, immediately to the north, and it would actually be the north and east of Main Street and First Street,
we would be identifying 36 parking spaces that they would be able to use, they'd be able to sort of allow,
and they would also be paying for the raw material so we can seal that parking lot.
It's been sometimes, and that's been done, and that's going to be a nice upgrade for downtown.
The key thing that we want to point out is that these are incentives to be able to have this done,
but we consider that we're going to be having 18 new single family homes built, and probably the one of the older areas of town.
I asked for information about this, we have, let's see, I believe there have been three building permits pull for new single family homes since January 23,
or 2014, not a whole lot of activity there.
Well, we're going to be able to do, we'll have new 18 new homes, they're going to be people living in there,
going to be utility customers, the miners exchange building, instead of that being barely used and getting about $300 a month,
we're going to have new units in it, all the way up to the fifth floor, and each one of those we estimate will probably have utility bills somewhere to $250 to $300 each.
So, the fees that we're waiving, the lots that we're giving them are transferring ownership to are just sitting there.
It's basically foul and it's a cost to us, we have to move them, we have to take care of them.
We're putting it into production views.
So I think this is a very positive thing from Miami.
We're really happy this is happening.
And if you want to hear Tammy, you can give us a quick update on the project if you'd like.
Yeah, that's it.
Well, we are so excited.
We've actually been really busy the last two months.
We've had surveyors and environmental consultants and just about everybody.
We've given more pastoral or one for us money.
I was money getting in the last few months, but actually the architect is going to be in town tomorrow
and delivering the plan set that 100% plan.
Submit set for building permit on the historic money exchange building.
And the houses hopefully are going to be later this week as well.
So we have been working with all of our investors and we have the big picture put together and we're hoping for our closing.
Between August 30th and September 15th, we're a little bit about two weeks behind.
We're hoping for August 30th, but we think no way to then September 15th.
Then we have a job super hired Tom.
I'm totally driving the bike from the last name at the moment, but he'll be in about town.
Trying to get information on anybody wants to bid the project.
Local contractors, vendors, suppliers.
And really hope and have that project out to bed in the next two weeks so we can get dirt moving.
Do you think you have enough local contractors to get to work complete?
We talked about it last December.
If I had been really honest, we tried very hard.
We're very committed to getting as many local people as possible.
It's an aggressive schedule and we have about a year construction schedule for both components of that.
So all 42 total units.
And sometimes that's a little bit of a challenge for some of the local crews that have a smaller crew working for them.
I usually see it.
Usually it's about 40 to 50% local subcontractors.
If you consider local if you expand that local perimeter, you know, to drop in.
And some of those close by areas.
I think that that number goes up substantially.
But the general contractors actually have a St. Louis just based on their historic conversion expertise.
We wanted to make sure that we had somebody that was really experienced.
That's a lot of kind of feel as you go process in the plans.
When you're working in those buildings and doing that into your demolition.
But the actual job super is out of job one, Tom and so he'll be very here close by and he's excited to do the project.
And he's done a couple projects for Debbie and I before so.
We're optimistic.
We'll we'll be leaving the set of plans here with Travis.
And as he's kind of going out and about we'll have them uploaded on a lot of the contractor websites and stuff that they can get those down.
Those those electronically.
But we will leave the fall set here for people as well that want to combine picks them up or look at those for local bits to make it accessible.
Yeah.
Can you tell us what the square frame is in the in the harvest time building what what those units are going to be?
It's going to be a combination of one and two bedroom apartments.
And they're there.
It's a little bit weird configuration because of the historic.
work nature, kind of, I have to keep some of those hallways. But the two hundred minutes
are about 950 square feet. The one bedrooms, I think are like 700, maybe 730 square feet.
There's a couple that are in weird locations that might be a little bit less than that, more
you know, close to that 700 mark. But there's 24 combination. It's heavy on the two bedrooms.
And I'm sorry, I don't actually have it in front of me, and I don't remember at the top
of my head. But it's heavy on the two bedrooms. So it's predominantly of those 24 units, I'd
say maybe 17 or 18 of them are two bedrooms, and then there's a smaller portion of one
bedrooms. And then all of the houses are three bedroom, two bath, one car garage. And
there are about 1,250 living square foot, and then there's an additional garage. It's about 450 square
foot for the total foot part to the house. I think that what's been exciting for us. We've been working
a lot with Christian Travis and they are amazing. I work with a lot of cities and a lot of stuff and they
are amazing. But kind of shelf on around a few of those lots, I think we move like maybe 5 of them
from the original list that we gave you guys into December that you guys passed and approved.
And as we were kind of hauling around trying to talk to some private owners about switching a few
of those lots, we actually ended up purchasing a couple of local lots to infill those and configuring
them a little bit better. But I've talked to two or three people that were excited about the project
that had maybe been sitting on lots or sitting on rehabs that they had been holding off just
because nothing's been happening in that downtown area. And that as, you know, they're hearing
that momentum and they're really seeing things start to happen that they're like, hey, that's great.
And I want to take advantage of that. I'm going to start working on this house. Maybe maybe maybe we'll see
those building permits go up a little bit. So it's exciting to see that momentum already kind of
start to spread a little bit. So your floor plans look the same. The floor plans were actually
deciding they've been working on the historic building, which mechanical on, you know, maybe
piano means a lot more complicated. So we're deciding between two or three floor plans. There's
really no greater grouping. Most of the groupings are like four houses. So even if we do two
different floor plans and then change the exterior of elevation on each of those so you'll have kind of
four distinct different looks. So we're not going to put four houses that look identical next to each
other. But there's definitely two and we're contemplating putting in a third floor plan just to
break up the variety a little bit. But most of the groupings that's grouping some about four houses
together. So I think that that would be a good mix if we change that elevation. And obviously we'll
change the colors and stuff out to make it huge attractive. That's my favorite.
Of the Dean of the parking lot that we have here highlighted the 36 spaces. How many total spaces are in
that wall? Oh, they're well over 100. I'm wanting to think about 100 to 120. And it's not a highly
use part of the space. No, it's not a concern for no. One of the other churches I know they use it.
I, you know, one day out of the week, I don't think that's going to be that much of a problem.
Now, I have had some concerns about making sure that we don't reserve the spots that are near some of the active businesses.
So, as I was saying, directly behind some of the business.
Exactly. We want to make sure that those are lots open.
So, you know, eyeballing this, probably a little bit further to the north and probably toward the middle is what we would be identifying.
And, by the way, 36 came to one and a half spaces per unit.
If you're wondering where 36 came from.
So, we'll work with them and we'll work with the property owners along there and identifying the spaces and we'll identify.
But, again, the farther north you get, you rarely have cars there.
So, there will still be ample parking there.
I hope in the future we have parking problems, right?
Yeah.
Thank you, too.
I don't want you to write a thing. It's really great.
We're going to try to plan and we've kind of been waiting how long a little bit just until we got to do that planning process and really we're ready to close.
But, we're going to try to make it a little ribbon cutting yourself through to the downtown business.
So, this will definitely keep you guys posted, let you know what's happening.
But, we'd like to memorialize the event and just get the word out that I'm pretty sure what's happening and kind of get that excitement for us.
Maybe an open house.
We'll definitely do an open house at completion.
We just thought we'd maybe do kind of like a groundbreaking on the Friday and just thought, I really know what's doing and kind of get the clock to be on.
So, people can kind of start watching and see that information get out there and then we'll definitely do a big formal open house or that.
Yeah.
We've got a shuffle board for playing for that.
So, we're going to have a really cool open house that may or may not involve shuffle board purposes.
I don't know.
So, you might have said this during the remodel of harvest time.
Are you also going to be doing construction of homes as well?
So, I'm going to say this a little bit.
So, we'll actually come on much sooner.
Ideally, we actually were just modeling today.
Ideally, I would love if we can keep the moment up to get those foundations in the small cell.
I think that we'll see houses turning as early as February March.
And they really will get those houses like in groups of four every couple weeks after that.
So, we very, may very well have all the houses least, you know, by summer when we actually finished the mining exchange building and start this in there.
Good.
That would be ideal.
Thank you.
Anything else?
Right.
I just needed extra on the out of.
Being going to get through the, the reality of this as far as giving away property and the reasons we can do this.
Well, housing is, of course, a core government function.
So, don't see any particular problems with it at all.
Okay.
So, that's it.
I'll make a motion.
Okay.
So, I can write.
Second.
question. Aye. Forster. Aye. The list. Aye. Johnson. Aye. Aye. Aye. I'm 15
ribbid, so 17 days 12 was transferred so before in the amount of $46,000. $46,290. Approved contract with
Marion County, who I'll say an author of C. Mandarin City Attorney, to sign those
proceed once on a card document. I've been receiving Kevin. Kevin. Kevin. Kevin. Kevin.
Kevin. Kevin. We're here before you to save me to ask you to award the bid to the Marion
County Company, which is also the company that is currently building the animal shelter.
And what this is forced to put a cap on the entire floor at the solid waste facility.
Years and years of scraping has actually worth a concrete back down to the rebar where we have
rebar exposed in the floor in a number of different places. And it's just becoming a safety hazard
to not only the employees, but to the people who come in and dispose of their waste.
We received two bids on this. I will tell you one was substantially higher than the other.
I don't know, sir. We have done our research in our homework with the Marion Company and even
had a confirmation email again today that they understand the specs fully. So we feel pretty
comfortable about awarding in the bid. I want to say that I was kind of curious why the big difference
I have talked to both companies and the concrete company themselves. Any of the concrete
supply in the concrete. And again, upon Christ's recommendation, we had them to confirmation email today
that they understood exactly what was required and they did. Okay. It's going to be a lot of prep work on the floor
and you will hate to wrap the services for. They're actually going to port in two phases. They're just going
to come in and clean real well, then they'll pull one side, let it cure out, then they'll pour the other side.
This is something that's going to be scheduled on maybe a day that you guys are not open or is it
you're going to have to shut services down. We're just going to run the half of our floor,
which is going to be difficult, but it's going to be more than a one-day process. Right. So
we'll just work around it the best we can. And this was a budget that I'm being, yes, they've come under
budget. Yes. Significant way. What was it? And then that's how you want to put it back.
What was that? 60s? 60s. Yeah, 60s. Yeah. I'm making most of our proof. I'll second. I thought you
want to create a finish. Johnson? I think. Johnson? I think.
Forster? Hi. Lewis? Hi. Western? Hi. I'm 16. I mean, previous one is what you've
50 cents a segment and we missed where we totaled those to fund part and recreation being
Mayor Protem, this item of the following item are the actual ordinances that will put into effect
the broadening of the dollar fifty search arjun municipal utility bills and then the following
one is also the modification of the Convention of Tourism Advisory Board. We discussed this at our last meeting
in quite a bit of depth with the key reason here is to start launching more of a sports advisory
in sports authority that we've identified as being one of our major needs in town for our community
and also modifying the CBB so we would have a much larger and active CBB that will oversee
quite a bit of the these activities that are taking place. So these are the ordinances that will put it into place so we can get started
is the CBB able is this something that will be able to handle.
Well, actually I we joke about it but I want to thank Amanda because a lot of her vision and
what this can do for us not only for our kids not only for visitation in Miami but also for revenue
it was kind of eye opening and coming from Branson I know that sports marketing was a big issue there
that we were working on but it's amazing even a town like Miami. It brings a lot of people in our community
to spend money and but also at the same time is providing something for our next generation which I think is very important.
We discussed both these at our CBB board meetings and Brian's been involved in landing so we've been through this and I didn't know where you all had any concerns or questions about it.
I think it's a it's a it's a great thing that we're looking into this you know I look around the room and I know there's a nice small children
anytime we do functions usually are leaving the city and going somewhere else for your kids for sports.
Yeah, we're missing out on a lot to be able to provide whether it's tournaments or something here and we need to capitalize on that.
I think there's a lot of good things out there that can be done to make Miami a place that everybody says, you know we got to go to the Miami to do a tournament or to capitalize on that so that's great.
I think that emotional.
I make a motion.
Second it.
Forester.
Hi.
Who is?
I.
Justin.
Hi.
I think the ordinance abolishing the board of parks and recreation, demanding the Miami Convention
and terrorism advisory board.
Also, one is the mine commission and bills.
It's real.
Also, one is the my.
Commission.
It's not a redundant, it's not how I feel you better than you.
I mean, the number of more members of this son and certain additional duties there,
too, providing for a call of education, providing serve of ability, and establishing an effective
date.
Then, I think I just made my comments on that before, so it's part of the package.
Again, we really like the idea of enlarging our CVB.
We have a very good one right now in their act of enlarging it, we'll be able to start over
seeing the programs that we're going to be undertaking in regard to sports and sports marketing.
You know, I'll also go make the motion.
Well, I'll imagine you've been by favors for me and I mean, okay, mind, did you look
at it also?
Yes, go.
Am I good?
Thank you.
May the motion approve.
Second.
Nevermind.
I'll end up.
Louis?
Hi.
What is it?
I.
18.
Me and I were in this number of 16-year-olds times, right, eight times, section one, per
day or seven, to your flight, nine, change with the five from Gerald Fountain, mind, and special
utility authority prime.
This is just a housekeeping item, and when we created the rainy day fund and established on
the ordinance in 2013, in section one, paragraph, step seven, it states that the rainy
day funds are included with the general fund in there in our audit.
And there are actually the funds actually originated in the mind, especially utility authority,
so we would like to continue to put them include them with that fund instead of the general
fund.
So we're just asking to change the name in that one section.
I'm going to go.
No.
Go.
I'm going to go.
I like the most to approve.
Second.
Johnson?
Hi.
Louis?
I.
So in your packet, is that that contract, I'd like to go back on the history a little bit.
About a year ago, CMAR Review Committee was established, it included for City staff and
one council member.
We did a pretty thorough research and came back with a recommendation to hire crossline
construction.
But at the following meeting, the Council did pass a resolution stating that the CMAR process is a good delivery method to actually rehabilitate the Civic Center.
It is a budgeted project that was the discussion we had about using the money from the rainy day fund.
And actually the very first repayment to the rainy day fund is going to happen this year also.
I want to point out that the construction manager's fee is 6%.
And that is of the guaranteed maximum price.
And that'll be their first, if you approve this contract,
that'll be their very first, actually,
amendment to this contract.
They will meet with city staff and whatever architect
we hire to come up with a plan, which would include pricing
and that guaranteed maximum price would include their fee.
And it is part of our comprehensive plan
about community facilities and spaces maintaining those.
Time is lucky.
OK.
And you guys will set the guaranteed maximum price.
It's not guaranteed.
I mean, we have set up to 2 million,
but depending on what they come back with,
you guys can set it.
You can take things out.
You can change whatever you feel comfortable.
So you still have control.
Because at this point, it's just saying they can start working on it.
OK.
With our current, what we believe we did in house
with what we did down the hall, is there still
options for us to do that, not that we have the staff
for all that.
Well, we kind of have learned the hard way
that we actually needed way more planning.
We're not experts in building.
We're becoming them very quickly.
But that's three mistakes.
And this is a huge project.
And we would feel better if professionals actually helped us.
And this, the same method, the CMAR construction manager at risk,
was actually used for the stadium as well.
And we originally talked about this.
There was a bigger price tag.
Yes.
And they still good with, around what we're looking at now.
Yes, that was my first conversation with them lately.
I said, OK.
So we've reduced it to a full of what we originally kind of thought.
And they said they're still better.
That's good.
Definitely.
Awesome.
Actually, Matt, it was here from Cossillon.
If you need to talk to somebody from Cossillon.
I hate for it.
I've got to drive all this way.
I don't see some questions.
That's all right.
I know we got GH2 on here next.
Is Cossillon doing anything the architect work or you're still
going with GH2's recommendations?
Well, that's the CMAR process.
And stop me if I'm wrong or correct me, David.
There's a design build, which is one contract for the city council.
And then there's CMA, our construction manager, where
it's going to that's two contracts.
So the two contracts would include the construction manager,
and then it would also include the architect.
So the council would have two contracts versus one.
So we would have to hire.
I haven't seen the new plans, but we did review the plans
it and there was a kind of a puzzle we were moving pieces around and we've made it much
more simple and that's by what we talked about during the tour moving, actually switching
finance with court and making that also our council chambers.
Last discussion I don't remember the chamber, the chamber wasn't, council chamber wasn't
going to move it from the now that it is.
Yes, it's all about security when there were about a year ago there were actually less than
a year ago.
There was that same Bernadette shooting and that really kicked us in to get going.
We need to at least secure those windows, the customer service windows and then it kind
of started thinking differently.
We don't know where the public is in the building at any one given time.
So if we were to have an emergency say in earthquake or you know who knows what, we wouldn't
know where the public is and by keeping them in one area except for the banquet room and of
course the gym, at least we would know there would be in those few places not anywhere.
Again, when you go into the county court house, you know, you know, you know, through a secure area.
This is as calm as it can be anymore and we're just introducing that.
I want to move the place department of France, you know, the place presence is different.
Everything's still on the table, though.
Yeah.
And that's a question, nothing is fore plan and everything is nothing's been said.
No, that's what we need them to help them to start with G8C and work it out.
But if you have thoughts other than what we have said tonight, then you need to tell us and I'll
just plan that.
No, I think what you guys are ultimately, yeah, we're going to try to speak for the public.
You know, I'd still like to get the feedback.
I mean, you raise a great point.
Place department of works better for the public over there than it does back there.
I just asked the thing, you know, everybody has a little bit of opportunity to, you know,
maybe what's out there?
You know, what would you like to see and your city hall and that was the point we made in the comprehensive
plan and in the budget is that this is the people's building and more so than most city halls,
because this isn't civic center, that's why this facility was built.
So try to take it back.
So if somebody's saying, why are you spending money on it, it's not just for offices.
This is for the function and this is so people, the citizens know that they can come here and have
events and programs and it's just something for my Emma, which is what the design was back in
55 to 67.
I'd like somebody who would want to have to address that parking lot back there, but probably sooner
than later.
Yeah.
It's pretty bad.
If I ask, I'd like to motion approve.
I'll second it.
Chances?
I.
Louis.
I'm 28.
Jes.
Two octaves.
We'll go on a 13.
Yeah.
13. Do you want to go back to dance? Yeah. He's in a pro-law. I know. There's a lot. I'm sure you're sick
of hearing from me. Back in 2013, January of 2013, the council approved a master contract with
the judge to architect. This would be workload or number 13 towards that contract. They would work
with staff and Krosslin to come up with that plan, which would include the guaranteed maximum
prize. I said gross maximum prize, but it's guaranteed maximum prize. I do want to point out that
GH2's fee is 6.9%. And again, this is a budget item. It is part of our comp plan. And our first
repayment back to the rainy day fund after we borrow from it is this year. So if you guys have any questions?
About three. What was that? Three. Fifty years. What was the amount I can remember?
For what? For the payback. 166,000 for the first payback. And then 305. Okay. Okay.
So the GH2 and Krosslin can work with staff. You guys are going to come in here. It's going to do the same
people minus the council, but we're going to have obviously had him involved. So I guess it wouldn't be minus
the council, and it would just, it'll be Kevin, Browning, Travis, myself, and Doug. Good.
They should all complains to Doug. Exactly. We're going forward to the number.
That would jump. That's it. Good for motion. Yep. Motion proof. Sorry.
Weston. Aye. Forster. Aye. Lewis. Aye. Joseph. Aye. Neil, if I could just one last thing before we move off,
we're going to see with Kevin sitting here. If you walk around the building, especially areas are probably
not going to be renovated as part of this project we're talking about, it's still remarkable when
you see how much work has been done, just new paint, changing out ceiling tiles and cleaning those. Just
just a lot of very good basic work that is just freshening up the building as we indicate it. We're about
to reinstall the steps on the north side of the building. So people will be able to get in much easier. I just want
to compliment Kevin and his staff because anytime you walk in, they've got a project going and
it's becoming more and more noticeable every single day and it's wanted to thank him. And not only
this building but a lot of other buildings that were working on today. Thank you Kevin. I'm turning one
out of new business, didn't you? Not done this agenda. Mr. Chairman. Yes, sir. Just FYI, we got in a
tort playing notice this afternoon. So we're starting the process of evaluating that and contacting
the insurance company. So just let you know. Okay, thank you sir. I'm 22 in May and Councilor Union now.
That's good, thank you.
Brian, schools back in session.
Yep.
I just want to make a quick, I believe this is David Anderson's last very good
council meeting and I just want to say thank you for serving your city.
I thank you, Donna.
It's a great job.
You've done a city a great job and we appreciate that, David.
So, I do see you most in the case.
Here are my communications over to Mike Edwards and Sean Neconic, also in the dissociates.
Earlier today, Brian's shot me a couple of emails just wondering about some updates and
especially wondering where we're at on the road projects and also wanting to get an update
on how we've been doing with the Dura patcher on the many, many, many potholes that we have
in town and asking you shall receive and we thought since they're both here in town and
no time like the present, plus we also are planning some things with the public to try to
get some input on it.
We thought we could kind of a quick update.
Sure.
So, I'm going to turn it over to them.
Sean, I'm going to have a working on your comprehensive plans for your street and your utilities.
Currently, this week, I've been driving about every town in Miami.
I'm probably 75% done, so I plan to finish that this week.
Right now, basically, I'm videotaping everything.
Driving up and down every road and I'm giving a condition rating on pavement and curving
gutter on a one to five scale and then that kind of helps me go back in and program where we need
to start and then we will take the utility plan and then throw that in with it and then try and
start coming up with an order to this thing on where to be in.
So, this week, I plan to be done with at least gathering up most of my assessment stuff and
then kind of start trying to put this thing together, Dean and myself and Mike have talked
about trying to get some public comment and we feel that probably okay, open house type deal.
Here at the Civic Center would probably be the best scenario for that just a couple hours.
However long we need to, just one evening, have people come in, we get set up some maps,
maybe some comment forms and then just meet with fam and see where they want us to start working
at and then kind of work those comments into the plan as well.
So, everyone feels like they had a voice in this.
I do that.
I asked Dean to just kind of update us, you hear out in the public real quick, why in the world are we
overlaying this, whatever you got this and I appreciate, many times I would like to,
I thought about putting it going pro-long and driving around myself, but you know, you
You mentioned you drive through and you look at the conditions and that is there's many variables and and I can't express enough what you said with the public and if you can get it out there
You know, we don't just go through and say, oh the squeaky wheel gets great first. I mean, there's going to be a priority to this and just because a condition is one thing
How traffic in one area is something else and and I want to take all of those items into consideration and I want the public whatever we decide to do
I don't want you know I'm pleading for them to show up and and everybody have a voice into this because you know
Ultimately we look at what needs to be done and Mike goes doing does a great job with his staff
But people have questions and a lot of times they have more opinions in regards to how we should do it and without getting the answers you know that we would like to give them. So I think that's great
You know, I don't know if you've got somebody from city staff that's going around with you on some of these or when you turn it back in I would you know I'd like to see what we come up with
And then you can look at you know is that well you know you got two houses on that road is it a high traffic area because we you know we probably get so much money to and how we allocate it's going to be very important so
What aspect of this to that I think is very important number one remember that they have a deliverable to us of October 31 so this isn't just a study that we may get one day we wanted in a couple of months
But the second thing too is it's not just a study of what streets but how we go about it one of the things that we've talked about quite a bit is that in all probability a lot of times we have our crews doing things they shouldn't be doing
Maybe an overlay of the of a large street like just for each and we're jee street. They go to great job. I'm not saying they shouldn't have done it, but
But those are some of the ones that once we have a plan probably we can have an economy of scale where we can go out and engineer and have a bid on any number of streets probably very similar to the microsurfacing that we've just done.
And hit those streets with contractors that can go in have the equipment get it done very quickly.
And then that would then free up our plan so we would have our crews fixing the pot holes doing the soft spots the utility cuts and things such as that so it's not just what streets but how we go about going to those streets.
And granted we talked about this on a how many times that sometimes we've dug them out and put in concrete and those streets are going to be great but was it really necessary.
Can we be better off with maybe a million overlay or a slurry seal or something like that.
I think our citizens just basically want to street where they're not having the fillings and their teeth not to lose when they drive on.
And they made up necessarily always be pretty but if we can have a smooth ride that's what we're trying to get.
No I agree with you on that percent I think just the educational aspect of what we're doing and how we're doing it to you know.
Some people don't think in the lines of others and I believe that you know, I read somewhere where somebody maybe is on social media
You know, that's gray, but why did you pour a concrete behind you know
And they, you know, basically I think somebody said you know, it's because now they've had buried lines and for fire safety
It's a great thing and those are the small things sometimes people just don't realize so
Sean, if I'm going to put you on the spot very quickly, but what you've seen so far versus other cities how do you compare us?
But I'm 20 years old
Kind of wanting to see somebody you know, it's looking at it through new odds
It is there are some very poor areas, but your count is a lot older than a lot of them that I've worked in too
So you also have to look at that aspect of it. Well
You also have to look at where you're placed. I mean you're here between two rivers and
Your subsoil is not all that great around here
So it does take a little bit more to keep the roads up on top of the ground where they belong
You do have several aspects playing against you, but
On all for the age of the town. It's probably not too much worse off than other places
My comment
How does our work on our pottole with our new pottole patch are those holding up pretty good or yes, sir
The pottole patcher when we put with the material in the holes now it's staying and it don't come out
Our old way of putting the hot mix and the cold mix in every time it rang traffic drove on it
Just pop right out. We were going back and we fixed on the same one
So far it stayed in every single hole. We put it in
We encourage the traffic to drive on it the final part of it is you put a small little beat of
Channel on the top side of it
We want the traffic to drive on that that packs it down it pushes it in and then we'll come back a little bit later
And sweep up the few remaining chips. We put the chips on top one to help pack it down
But too, so the oil does it get on the citizens cars when I happen in the cars, but it's working great
The guys love it. They're really starting to get the hang out, but now two weeks before school started
We went out for the solid two weeks and tried to
I say get caught up on the pot hose. I don't know that that's really a
realization
The solid two weeks every day all day and use the pot whole patch of them two weeks. We went through three tanks of oil in them two weeks
We easily get around 275 200 50 gallons when we go we get some each time
On our normal weekly schedule. We take it out every Thursday and we start in an award
Generally like
We start down here from Steve. I want to central and from the truck route to the industry
We start in there. We just do that whole area
Some areas like that takes our hour and a half some of them take four or five hours. Just depends on how bad the potiles are and
We just start working our way around the town
Ideally be if we could follow right behind the sweeper, but he's so far ahead of us. He's gonna all have us
But it is working really good
Some of you might have noticed and I think Dean made the call with the trucker out. You know, I know what would you stand up them?
We only have it on and we more they're all staying in there
So it's the guys really like it
We lost we could put a number how much back then excited to spread with him the longer
Well, I don't have the exact number, but I do know that the code makes that we were buying
Is around ninety five dollars a ton the hot mix if we bought that it's about sixty one sixty two dollars a ton the panel price of oil
This right here we're getting it for about thirty five dollars a ton of the time we buy the chips in the oil
Make it tons worth it's about thirty five dollars and it varies how many holes you can get depending on the size of the hole and the depth and stuff
But they're seven in the redo. Yeah, we don't have to go back. So you don't really have
Schedule per se you say you've got it. Is this thing only go out once a week and we take every Thursday
We would you know say we're gonna hit word one or then more to we're just gonna start
Well, we're only first started we started out in the Northwest
Started out in green acres. We just kind of did little four box sections at a time
Worked away through town and kind of working our way back through town
So we're just you know kind of working but that two weeks that we went out
I asked the jet guys to
Go around the schools really well some of the bus routes some of the main thoroughfares get them before school started
So right now. I think they're working over in that area
I just told y'all about down there by loves kind of working that area ahead and north and they'll just do four five block sections at a time
And then we also somebody calls in a pile. We go take care of it
You know
larger street streets that are too far gone. This really doesn't apply. I mean this but the few pot holes that works well
Seeing a couple of mics crews out there and just stopped and asking about it
And one thing they also have mentioned that they like about it is that you know, it doesn't come out
But if there is any settling or something like that
Which can happen at least what is settled can be built upon?
Isn't so we may have to go back if there's some settle method and put it back in
But at least you're adding something that is more permanent rather than something that just gets washed out the next rainstorm
Next winter storm
Oh, oh patches I'm saying it look pretty good and the factor holding up right there. It's not something
Yeah, they're holding up it. It actually seals it off. It's a
Permanent fix really you know for that pot hole and we're like things that we're not having to go back and do them over again and again
It's it's a great tool. It's I'm glad we've purchased it. Yeah
I'm not to put you in spot again, but you said hot
31 31st is one of the worst places
When we will try to decide to get maybe a public
No, no, no, we want the public input.
There's more than that.
So that becomes part of the plan that we're going to provide you.
So the public input, we're talking about in maybe a two or three weeks.
Right, actually.
Earlier for this side, scheduled to bank, but we're in for it.
So, we need to get that in social media, and the paper we'll focus with that.
Yes, I was going to work on it tomorrow, get something out, and get something to do.
Yeah, we need to have that as part of the plan that we're part of.
So, once you get the plan, we put it into place.
And you may consider doing a second one.
Maybe after you get the plan together, and everybody's kind of in agreement.
Maybe you do one more, and let them know where you're going to first and why.
And then kind of keep everybody in the loop.
So maybe that'll stop some of those fine calls of why you're doing this and not this.
And also with the process, too.
I mean, when you look at all the number of streets that we've handled with the microsurfacing.
And that project, I believe, the microsurfacing roughly, quarter of a million,
the striking that followed about the 2015's, 20,000.
And then we did the crack ceiling beforehand.
But adding everything together, that was probably about a $350,000 project.
And look at how many streets we touched.
So, by working on this, and remember, in our fiscal year,
plus we probably have some of this rolling over, we have a budget of a two and a half million.
So, we hope that with their help, with the economy of scale and all that,
that we could really hit quite a few streets in the next year.
Yeah.
Thank you, both.
Thank you, thanks.
And I'm y'all staying on that.
No, that's it.
Good.
On 24, exactly, say, percentage of 25.
Oh, we asked 307, B2.
And 307, and B1.
We're going to be going to exact the situation.
Like, most of all, it's exactly a session based on the provision right there.
How's that going to be?
Question?
Aye.
Orster?
All right.
I'm going to tell you that.